Remember everything. Forgive nothing.
The Bourne Ultimatum is a action, drama, mystery
film directed by Paul Greengrass.
Bourne is brought out of hiding once again by reporter Simon Ross who is trying to unveil
Operation Blackbriar, an upgrade to Project Treadstone, in a series of newspaper columns.
Information from the reporter stirs a new set of memories, and Bourne must finally uncover
his dark past while dodging The Company's best efforts to eradicate him.
Jason Bourne, played by Matt Damon.
Nicky Parsons, played by Julia Stiles.
Noah Vosen, played by David Strathairn.
CIA Director Ezra Kramer, played by Scott Glenn.
Simon Ross, played by Paddy Considine.
Paz, played by Edgar Ramírez.
The Bourne Ultimatum is a 2007 American action-thriller film directed
by Paul Greengrass and written by Tony Gilroy, Scott Z.
Burns, and George Nolfi, based on a story by Gilroy.
The third installment in the Jason Bourne film series, the film was based on the 1990 novel of the same name by Robert Ludlum, and stars Matt Damon as former CIA assassin and psychogenic
amnesiac Jason Bourne, alongside an ensemble cast including Julia Stiles, David Strathairn, Scott Glenn, Paddy Considine, Édgar Ramírez, Albert Finney, and Joan Allen.
In the film, Bourne continues his search for information about his past before he was part
of Operation Treadstone and becomes a target of a similar assassin program.
Principal photography began in New York City on October 2, 2006.
The Bourne Ultimatum premiered at ArcLight Hollywood on July 25, 2007, before being
theatrically released on August 3 in the United States, by Universal Pictures.
It received acclaim from critics and grossed $444 million worldwide, becoming
Damon's highest-grossing film with a lead role at the time.
It was chosen by National Board of Review as one of the top ten films of 2007, and went on to win all three of its
nominations at the 80th Academy Awards: Best Film Editing, Best Sound Mixing, and Best Sound Editing.
A fourth film without the involvement of Damon, titled The Bourne Legacy, was released in August 2012, and the fifth film (a
direct sequel to Ultimatum that reprises Damon as the lead role), titled Jason Bourne, was released in July 2016.
The film explores themes of assassin, central intelligence agency
(cia), corruption, paris, france, based on novel or book.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and emotional.